tyndale.com 2018-12-29

# Tyndale | Privacy Policy

Effective May 25, 2018

Tyndale.com, the Internet site located at http://www.tyndale.com (the "Site"), is operated and maintained by Tyndale House Publishers ("Tyndale"). This Privacy Policy describes Tyndale's policies and procedures for the collection of personal information by this Site, and our use and dissemination of such information. If you do not feel comfortable with Tyndale's Privacy Policy, please do not use this Site or allow your children to use it.

From time to time Tyndale may revise this Privacy Policy. Therefore you should review it periodically so that you are up to date on our policies and practices. If there is a material change in those policies or practices that relate to the collection, use or disclosure of children's personal information, Tyndale will notify parents who have consented to their children providing us with such information in the past. If you want to communicate with us about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at: Tyndale House PublishersAttn: Internet Group351 Executive DriveCarol Stream, IL 60188Telephone: 630-784-5555Email: click here

Tyndale.com's policy is to respect and protect the privacy of our users. This policy's statement tells you how we collect information from you and how we use it. Using the internet should be a fun and positive experience and we want to help you enjoy it.

This Privacy Policy consists of two sections. Section I describes Tyndale's policies that apply to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information furnished to us by visitors to our Site who are age 13 and over. Section II describes the special additional policies Tyndale applies to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information about visitors to our Site who are under age 13. Parents should read both Sections to obtain a full understanding of Tyndale's privacy policies and practices.

I. POLICIES THAT APPLY TO INDIVIDUALS AGE 13 AND OVER COLLECTION OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION BY TYNDALE

General. Personally identifiable information about visitors to this Site (that is, information such as a visitor's name, email address, mailing address, or telephone number) is collected only when knowingly and voluntarily submitted. Such information may be requested in connection with our sweepstakes, contests, games, surveys, forums, subscription registrations, content submissions, chats, bulletin boards, guestbooks, requests for suggestions, visitors' requests for products or services, and visitors' requests for additional information. Tyndale does not require a visitor to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in the online activity he or she is interested in.

Joint Collection of Personal Information. Sometimes Tyndale collects Personal Information jointly with business partners or sponsors. The identity of the entities collecting Personal Information will be clear at the time your Personal Information is collected.

WHAT TYNDALE DOES (AND DOESN'T DO) WITH THE PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

General. Tyndale uses personally identifiable information only for the purpose for which it is submitted unless we disclose other uses at the time of collection, in which case you will have the opportunity to instruct us not to use your data in other ways (i.e., "opt-out").

Sharing Personal Information. Tyndale may share personally identifiable information in the following circumstances: 

  * With our affiliates or with some of our business partners who would like to send you information about their products or services if we have your consent to do so. When we collect your information you will have the opportunity to instruct us not to share your information in these ways (i.e., "opt-out"). 
  *   * With third parties (including our service providers and government entities) to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues. 

We may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant, or other lawful requests for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

LINKS/CO-BRANDED SITES

Tyndale has established relationships with advertisers and reputable business partners that allow visitors to our Site to link directly to sites operated by these partners. Some of these sites, may be "co-branded" with a Tyndale logo; however, they are not operated or maintained by Tyndale. These sites may collect personal information from you. This Privacy Policy will apply to any personal information we obtain in this manner from our partners.

Tyndale chooses its advertisers and business partners carefully. However, Tyndale is not responsible for the content or practices of web sites operated by third parties that are linked to our Site. These links are meant for the user's convenience only. Links to third party sites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement or approval by Tyndale of the content, policies or practices of such third party sites. We are not responsible for any information these sites may obtain and do not oversee their policies or practices in collecting personal information. Therefore, once you have left this Site via such a link, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party site.

This Site may also be linked to web sites operated by companies affiliated with Tyndale. Tyndale may share information collected by these affiliated companies; however, this Privacy Policy will apply to any personal information we receive in this manner. Visitors to our affiliated sites should still refer to their separate privacy policies and practices when providing any personally identifiable information.

NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

When visitors come to our Site, we collect and aggregate information indicating, among other things, which web pages were visited, the order in which they were visited, and which hyperlinks, if any, were "clicked" by the visitor. Tyndale, like most major web sites, collects such information by placing small bits of information, known as "cookies", on the hard drive of your computer to log IP addresses, operating system (e.g., Windows or Macintosh), type of browser software (e.g., Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer), and Internet service providers (e.g., AOL or NET.COM) used by each visitor to the Site.

Cookies enable us to do a number of things to make your visit and future visits to the site more enjoyable. For example, cookies allow a visitor to quickly log on to a site he/she has used before by storing a password. By tracking how many people visit our Site and where they go, we are able to determine which part of the Site users like the best, which part needs some improvement and what changes should be made. By obtaining this information, we are able to continually improve our Site and bring you the best online experience possible.

Although the cookie itself does not collect any personally identifiable information about a visitor, and Tyndale does not use cookies in order to obtain such information, the cookie can be used to determine the IP address of the visitor's Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of his or her point of connectivity to the Internet. Tyndale may also disclose some of the non-personally identifiable information we obtain to advertisers to inform them how many people have seen or linked to their advertisements on our Site. However, we do not disclose personally identifiable information to these advertisers. Visitors may also receive cookies from third parties, but Tyndale cannot control the content of these cookies.

Tyndale does not save credit card information in a cookie.

For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

Our Site can contain pixel tags, web beacons, and clear gifs embedded in web pages, videos, or emails, allow a web server to read certain types of information from your browser, check whether and when you have viewed a particular web page or email message, and determine, among other things, the IP address of your computer and the URL of the web page from which the pixel tag was viewed.

You should consult your browser owner's manual for instructions on how to refuse cookies.

REVIEWING AND MAKING CHANGES TO PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

Visitors may review or delete personal information from our records at any time. If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by filling this form. According to the Privacy Shield Principles, the EU GDPR, and other applicable privacy laws, you have the right to:

  * Know what Personal Information Tyndale has about you;
  * Ensure your Personal Information is accurate and relevant for the purposes for which Tyndale collected it; 
  * Make your Personal Information portable to another data controller;
  * Withdraw your consent to Tyndale processing your Personal Information; and 
  * Have your Personal Information erased.

If you would like to review, correct, receive a copy of, or erase the Personal Information we have about you or withdraw your processing consent, please send us your request using our contact page (click here) or write to us at Tyndale House Publishers Attn: Internet Group, 351 Executive Drive, Carol Stream, IL 60188 . Unless a legal exemption applies, we will respond to all such requests within thirty (30) days. If you would like to know whether we have collected personal information about you, please provide us with the activities that you participated in on the Site, which requested personal information. After we have reviewed the relevant databases, we will confirm whether we have collected such information about you. Prior to changing or deleting such information, we require that you provide us with proof of your name and address, such as a valid driver's license. Once we have received such proof and determined that it is satisfactory, we will immediately delete or modify your information in our database and refrain from collecting any other personally identifiable information from you, if you so request. However, there may be residual information that will remain within our databases that may or may not contain personally identifiable information. This residual information will not be given to any other third party or used for any commercial purpose.

Additionally, when you make a purchase or attempt to make a purchase through the Site, we collect certain information from you, including your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, and phone number. We refer to this information as “Order Information.” Your payment information is collected by our payment processor (Cybersource) and is not stored within our Site.

When we talk about “Personal Information” in this Privacy Policy, we are talking about both Device Information and Order Information.

SECURITY AND INTEGRITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Tyndale has established and maintains reasonable procedures to protect the confidentiality, security, and integrity of Personal Information collected by this Site.

We hold your Personal Information in a combination of hard copy and electronic files for the period necessary to support the Site, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, or otherwise fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy. Even after you cancel your account, copies of some information from your account may remain viewable in some circumstances where, for example, you have shared information with social media or other services. We may also retain backup information related to your account on our servers for some time after cancelation for fraud detection or to comply with applicable law or our internal security policies. We do not always remove or delete all of your non-personally identifiable account information for a number of reasons due to technical and systems constraints, or contractual, financial, or legal requirements.

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. If Tyndale learns of a security breach that may affect your data, we will notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. We may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues related to your use of the Site.

II. ADDITIONAL POLICIES THAT APPLY TO CHILDREN UNDER 13 KIDS AND INTERNET SAFETY

We at Tyndale understand that the Internet presents an opportunity for us to reach the public in new and exciting ways with information about our programming, fun games, exciting sweepstakes and contests, email, chat rooms, bulletin boards, and other forms of interactivity. Tyndale also recognizes the privacy concerns of parents, and the importance of protecting the privacy of the information this Site collects from children. Parents of children who visit this Site can be confident that any personal information that may be provided to this Site will be collected and maintained in accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"). Tyndale encourages parents to supervise their children's activities online and to participate with their children's online activities whenever possible. However, we understand that parents may not always be able to supervise their children's activities on the Internet. That's why Tyndale has developed a Site that parents can feel is safe for their children and kids will find cool, informative, educational, and fun! Because there's always room for improvement, Tyndale welcomes any suggestions on how to make the Site a better, safer place to hang out.

COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION FROM CHILDREN UNDER 13

When a visitor to our Site is under the age of 13, Tyndale does not require the disclosure of more personally identifiable information than is reasonably necessary for him or her to participate in an activity as a condition of such participation.

Tyndale may use different types of personally identifiable information submitted to this Site by children under 13 in a variety of ways, which are described below. In each instance, we comply with the parental consent requirements of COPPA.

A. Use of a Child's Information by Tyndale

* We may collect a child's email address in connection with a contest, sweepstakes or game for the sole purpose of communicating with the child on a one-time-only basis (i.e., to contact a contest winner). This information will not be used to re-contact the child, and will be deleted from our records when the contest or game is over. Parental consent will be obtained before we send the winner a prize.

* We may collect a child's email address in order to respond more than once to a child's specific request. For example, the child may want to subscribe to an online newsletter or receive other online communications from Tyndale. In these instances Tyndale will also obtain a parent's email address along with the child's. Before any further contact with the child, Tyndale will send an email to the parent (a) notifying him or her we have collected the child's email address in order to respond more than once to the child's request for a subscription, information, etc; (b) informing the parent that he or she can refuse us permission to contact the child, and how to do so; and (c) informing the parent that if he or she does not respond to the email within 72 hours, Tyndale may use the child's information for the purpose for which it was submitted.

* We may collect a child's personally identifiable information (including name, email address, mailing address and phone number) for such activities as chats, forums, surveys, games, guestbooks, bulletin boards, requests for suggestions, subscription registrations, content submissions, requests for products or services, or requests for additional information. In these instances we will initially collect only the child's name and online contact information and the email address of the child's parent. Before using this information for any purpose, we will send the parent an email that (a) informs the parent that we wish to collect and use the child's personal information and need the parent's consent to do so, and (b) provides the parent with a link to access to this Privacy Policy, which describes our information collection and use policies as required by COPPA. If the proposed use of the child's personal information does not involve disclosure to a third party, then Tyndale will ask the parent to provide consent by return email. Upon receipt of the email consent, we will send the parent a confirming email. If the proposed use of the child's personal information involves disclosure to third parties, the email we send to the parent will ask the parent either to (i) return by postal mail or fax a consent form that will be attached to the email, or (ii) call a toll free number where consent can be given over the phone. If parental consent is not obtained by one of these methods within one week Tyndale will delete all of the child's and parent's personally identifiable information from its records. In addition, parents can revoke a prior consent at any time.

* We may collect a child's name and email address to the extent reasonably necessary to protect the security of this Site, to protect against liability or as required or permitted by law. Information collected for these reasons will not be used for any other purpose.

B. Sharing Children's Personal Information With Third Parties.

Tyndale may share a child's personal with other affiliates who may send you information about their products or services. These third parties have agreed to maintain the confidentiality, security and integrity of the personal information they obtain from Tyndale. As noted above, parents may exercise their option not to consent to the disclosure of their child's personal information to third parties. Parents may consent to Tyndale's collection and use of a child's personal information without consenting to the disclosure of the information to third parties.

LINKS/CO-BRANDED SITES

As noted in Section I of this Privacy Policy, this Site may link directly to sites operated by Tyndale House Publishers advertisers, business partners and affiliated companies. Those sites, which are not controlled by Tyndale House Publishers may collect personal information from your child. Parents should therefore check the relevant site's privacy policy to understand how it collects and uses children's personal information. Tyndale House Publishers will not share in any personal information obtained by a site from a child under the age of 13 unless that site follows the requirements of COPPA.

REVIEWING AND MAKING CHANGES TO PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION COLLECTED FROM CHILDREN UNDER 13

Parents of children under age 13 may review or delete personal information about their children from our records at any time. If you would like to know the types of personal information we collect, please contact us using the form on our contact page (click here) or write to us at Tyndale House Publishers Attn: Internet Group 351 Executive Drive, Carol Stream, IL 60188 . If you would like to know whether we have collected personal information about your child, please provide us with the activities that he or she participated in on the Site which requested personal information. After we have reviewed the relevant databases, we will confirm whether we have collected such information about your child. Prior to changing or deleting such information, we require that you provide us with proof of your name and address, such as a valid driver's license, and proof that your child resides with you or is otherwise in your custody. Once we have received such proof and determined that it is satisfactory, we will immediately delete or modify your child's information in our database and refrain from collecting any other personally identifiable information from your child, if you so request. However, there may be residual information that will remain within our databases that may or may not contain personally identifiable information. This residual information will not be given to any other third party or used for any commercial purpose.

YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THESE TERMS

By using this site, you signify your assent to Tyndale House Publishers and Tyndale.com. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our sites. Your continued use of the Tyndale.com and affiliated sites after the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.

This privacy policy is subject to change without notice and was last updated on May 25, 2018.

* * *

## Enter your email to opt out.
